<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM "BioC.dtd"><collection><source>BioC-API</source><date>20250207</date><key>collection.key</key><document><id>PMC5899202</id><infon key="license">CC BY</infon><passage><infon key="alt-title">AcMNPV 38K Mediates Dephosphorylation of P6.9 Lai et al.</infon><infon key="article-id_doi">10.1128/JVI.01989-17</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">PMC5899202</infon><infon key="article-id_pmid">29444944</infon><infon key="article-id_publisher-id">01989-17</infon><infon key="elocation-id">e01989-17</infon><infon key="issue">9</infon><infon key="kwd">baculovirus 38K P6.9 HAD phosphatase AcMNPV nucleocapsid assembly</infon><infon key="license">This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International license.</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lai;given-names:Qingying</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wu;given-names:Wenbi</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Li;given-names:Ao</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wang;given-names:Wei</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yuan;given-names:Meijin</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Yang;given-names:Kai</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Sandri-Goldin;given-names:Rozanne M.</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Yang;given-names:Kai</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Yang;given-names:Kai</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Yang;given-names:Kai</infon><infon key="section_type">TITLE</infon><infon key="title">KEYWORDS</infon><infon key="type">front</infon><infon key="volume">92</infon><infon key="year">2018</infon><offset>0</offset><text>The 38K-Mediated Specific Dephosphorylation of the Viral Core Protein P6.9 Plays an Important Role in the Nucleocapsid Assembly of Autographa californica Multiple Nucleopolyhedrovirus</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract_title_1</infon><offset>184</offset><text>ABSTRACT</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>193</offset><text>Encapsidation of the viral genomes, leading to the assembly of the nucleocapsids to form infectious progeny virions, is a key step in many virus life cycles. Baculovirus nucleocapsid assembly is a complex process that involves many proteins. Our previous studies showed that the deletion of the core gene 38K (ac98) interrupted the nucleocapsid assembly by producing capsid sheaths devoid of viral genomes by an unknown mechanism. All homologs of 38K contain conserved motifs of the haloacid dehalogenase superfamily, which are involved in phosphoryl transfer. The requirements of these motifs for nucleocapsid assembly, confirmed in the present study, suggest that 38K may be a functioning haloacid dehalogenase. P6.9 is also encoded by a core gene (ac100) and is required for viral genome encapsidation. It has been reported that multiple phosphorylated species of P6.9 are present in virus-infected cells, while only an unphosphorylated species is detected in the budded virus. Therefore, whether 38K mediates the dephosphorylation of P6.9 was investigated. An additional phosphorylated species of P6.9 in 38K-deleted or -mutated virus-transfected cells was detected, and the dephosphorylated sites mediated by 38K were determined by mass spectrometry. To assess the effects of dephosphorylation of P6.9 mediated by 38K on virus replication, these sites were mutated to glutamic acids (phosphorylation-mimic mutant) or to alanines (phosphorylation-deficient mutant). Studies showed that the nucleocapsid assembly was interrupted in phosphorylation-mimic mutant virus-transfected cells. Taken together, our findings demonstrate that 38K mediates the dephosphorylation of specific sites at the C terminus of P6.9, which is essential for viral genome encapsidation.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">ABSTRACT</infon><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>1959</offset><text>IMPORTANCE Genome packaging is a fundamental process in the virus life cycle, and viruses have different strategies to perform this step. For several double-stranded DNA (dsDNA) viruses, the procapsid is formed before genome encapsidation, which may require basic proteins that help to neutralize the nucleic acid charge repulsion to facilitate the compaction of the genome within the confined capsid space. Baculovirus encodes a small basic protein, P6.9, which is required for a variety of processes in the virus infection cycle. The phosphorylation of P6.9 is thought to result in nucleocapsid uncoating, while the dephosphorylation of P6.9 is involved in viral DNA encapsidation during nucleocapsid assembly. Here, we demonstrate that a haloacid dehalogenase homolog encoded by baculovirus core gene 38K is involved in nucleocapsid assembly by mediating the dephosphorylation of 5 specific sites at the C terminus of P6.9. This finding contributes to the understanding of the mechanisms of virus nucleocapsid assembly.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>2982</offset><text>INTRODUCTION</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>2995</offset><text>The family Baculoviridae includes a diverse group of insect viruses with large, double-stranded, circular DNA genomes that are packaged in rod-shaped, enveloped nucleocapsids. There are four genera of Baculoviridae: Alphabaculovirus (lepidopteran nucleopolyhedrovirus [NPV]), Betabaculovirus (lepidopteran granulovirus [GV]), Gammabaculovirus (hymenopteran NPV), and Deltabaculovirus (dipteran NPV). The Alphabaculovirus genus fall into two phylogenetic clades, representing group I and group II NPVs. Autographa californica multiple nucleopolyhedrovirus (AcMNPV) is in the genus Alphabaculovirus (type species, Autographa californica multiple nucleopolyhedrovirus) and was the first baculovirus to have its genome completely sequenced. During infection of insect cells, most well-characterized baculoviruses undergo a biphasic virus life cycle with the production of two phenotypic virions: budded virions (BVs) and occlusion-derived virions (ODVs). These two forms of virions have a common nucleocapsid structure and carry the same genetic information but differ in the origin and composition of their lipid envelopes. The BV acquires its envelope from the plasma membrane which is modified with viral proteins by budding from infected cells and is required for spreading infection among cells and tissues, while the ODV obtains its envelope from virus-induced intranuclear microvesicles within a peripheral area, called the ring zone (RZ), in the nuclei of infected cells and plays a role in infecting the midgut epithelial cells of a host to initiate primary infection.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>4569</offset><text>Baculovirus infection causes the nucleus to swell and form the virogenic stroma (VS), which is a nuclear compartment composed of homogenous fibrillar electron-dense mattes with electron-lucent intrastromal spaces. The VS is thought to serve as a molecular scaffold for the transcription and replication of viral DNA and the subsequent packaging of DNA and assembly of nucleocapsids. Studies have shown that the nucleocapsid morphogenesis of baculovirus begins with the formation of empty, nearly full-length capsid sheaths, and the nucleoprotein core is concentrated from the base to the apex of the capsid cylinder.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>5186</offset><text>Genomes of DNA viruses are compacted and packaged into virus particles with small basic proteins encoded by the host or virus. Some viruses directly utilize host histones for DNA packaging, such as polyomaviruses and papillomaviruses. Some viruses encode their own DNA-packaging proteins, e.g., adenoviruses and white spot syndrome viruses (WSSVs). Baculovirus encodes a protamine-like protein, P6.9, which is rich in arginine, serine, and threonine residues and is thought to bind and condense viral DNA for packaging into the capsid sheath. Protamine-like proteins belong to a large group of proteins that are involved in DNA binding, known as sperm nuclear basic proteins. Posttranslational modifications (PTMs) of these basic proteins may be involved in extensive cellular, epigenetic, and chromatin changes. Evidence suggests that newly synthesized P6.9 is transiently phosphorylated in infected cells prior to participation in nucleocapsid assembly. In our previous study, multiple phosphorylated species of P6.9 were identified in cells infected with wild-type (WT)-resembling virus vP6.9:HA, while only an unphosphorylated species was detected in BVs. The various phosphorylation states of P6.9 were reexamined by acetic acid-urea polyacrylamide slab gel electrophoresis (AU-PAGE) analysis, which showed that a ladder composed of 7 phosphorylated species (no. 1 to 7 in AU-PAGE) and 1 unphosphorylated species (no. 0 in AU-PAGE) of P6.9 was detected using samples derived from cells infected with the WT-resembling virus vPK1:FLAG; in addition, 22 phosphorylation sites in P6.9 were identified by mass spectrometry (MS). These included serines, threonines, and arginines. The protein kinase PK1 encoded by baculovirus is responsible for hyperphosphorylation of P6.9, as the deletion of pk1 resulted in abolition of the 3 slowest-migrating rungs of P6.9 species (no. 5 to 7 in AU-PAGE), which in turn regulated the maximal expression of viral very late genes and viral infectivity. In addition to PK1 specifically regulating the hyperphosphorylation of P6.9, other protein kinases of the host are thought to regulate the hypophosphorylation of P6.9. Thus, the phosphorylation status of P6.9 may be critical in the life cycle of baculoviruses.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>7436</offset><text>Encapsidation of the viral genomes, leading to the assembly of infectious progeny virions, is an essential step in the virus life cycle. During nucleocapsid assembly, P6.9 is dephosphorylated, and viral DNA is condensed and packaged with P6.9 to form a DNA-protein core in the capsid sheath. The phosphatases of the virus and/or host that are responsible for dephosphorylation of P6.9 have not yet been identified. Baculovirus 38K is encoded by a core gene found in all baculovirus, nudivirus, and polydnavirus genomes. It belongs to the 38K (baculovirus)/ROP9 (apicomplexa) family of the haloacid dehalogenase (HAD) superfamily and has been shown to be essential for encapsidation of viral genomes during virus infection. Practically all members of the HAD superfamily possess four highly conserved sequence motifs, DxD, S/T, K, and DD/GDxxxD/GDxxxxD, which are also present in 38K homologs. The majority of the enzymes in this superfamily, e.g., phosphate monoester hydrolases (phosphatases) or phosphoanhydride hydrolase P-type ATPases, are involved in phosphoryl transfer. Thus, whether 38K dephosphorylates P6.9 during nucleocapsid assembly was investigated.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">INTRO</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>8600</offset><text>In the present study, by constructing 38K mutant viruses, we investigated the requirement of the HAD conserved motifs in 38K for viral propagation and nucleocapsid assembly. The phosphorylated species of P6.9 present in 38K-deleted or HAD motif-mutated virus bacmid DNA-transfected cells were then examined, and one slower-migrating rung representing higher phosphorylation of P6.9 species (no. 8 in AU-PAGE) was detected compared to the results for the control virus. By using MS, we identified 5 phosphorylated sites at the C terminus of P6.9 that were dephosphorylated by 38K. To confirm that the interruption of nucleocapsid assembly in 38K-deleted-virus-transfected cells was due to the inability of 38K to dephosphorylate P6.9, we generated a recombinant virus with phosphorylation-mimic sites in P6.9. Our study determined that 38K is involved in nucleocapsid assembly by mediating the dephosphorylation of P6.9.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>9520</offset><text>RESULTS</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>9528</offset><text>Conservation analysis of 38K homologs.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>9567</offset><text>Baculovirus 38K is encoded by a core gene found in all baculovirus, nudivirus, and polydnavirus genomes. Amino acid alignments showed that the C-terminal region of 38K homologs is more conserved than the N-terminal region (Fig. 1A). To obtain an overview of 38K evolutionary relationships, 38K homologs from baculoviruses, nudiviruses, and polydnaviruses were selected for phylogenic studies. The phylogenetic tree showed evidence for two clades: all the baculovirus 38K homologs belonged to clade 1, while clade 2 contained 38K homologs from nudiviruses and polydnaviruses (Fig. 1B), indicating that 38K homologs from nudiviruses and polydnaviruses are more distant from those from baculoviruses. A conserved domain search from the NCBI Conserved Domain Search databases revealed that AcMNPV 38K belongs to the viral phosphatase superfamily. The region from amino acid (aa) 135 to 288 of AcMNPV 38K hits the IIIC subfamily of the HAD superfamily, which contains the enzymes involved in phosphoryl transfer. The characterized proteins within subfamily III are all phosphatases with four characteristic sequence motifs, DxD, S/T, K, and DD/GDxxxD/GDxxxxD, that are present in members of the HAD superfamily. The results of the multiple-sequence alignment showed that all the 38K homologs in the families Baculoviridae, Nudiviridae, and Polydnaviridae contain the HAD motifs; specifically, they are D140xD142, S177, K251, and D275D276 in AcMNPV 38K (Fig. 1A). These results suggested that 38K may function as a viral phosphatase.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">zjv009183497001b.jpg</infon><infon key="id">F1</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>11095</offset><text>Bioinformatics analysis of AcMNPV 38K. (A) Sequence alignment of 38K homologs. The conserved amino acids of HAD motifs in 38K homologs are outlined by rectangles and indicated above of the sequence alignment. The following abbreviations are used, with GenBank accession numbers in parentheses: AcMNPV, Autographa californica multiple nucleopolyhedrovirus (NP_054128.1); BmNPV, Bombyx mori nucleopolyhedrovirus (AFN09011.1); OpMNPV, Orgyia pseudotsugata multiple nucleopolyhedrovirus (NP_046255.1); SeMNPV, Spodoptera exigua multiple nucleopolyhedrovirus (CDG72408.1); AgseNPV, Agrotis segetum nucleopolyhedrovirus (YP_529744.1); LdMNPV, Lymantria dispar multiple nucleopolyhedrovirus (ANS70986.1); AgseGV, Agrotis segetum granulovirus (YP_006267.1); CpGV, Cydia pomonella granulovirus (NP_148872.1); SpliGV, Spodoptera litura granulovirus (NP_258356.1); NeabNPV, Neodiprion abietis nucleopolyhedrovirus (YP_667907.1); NeleNPV, Neodiprion lecontei nucleopolyhedrovirus (YP_025256.1); NeseNPV, Neodiprion sertifer nucleopolyhedrovirus (YP_025256.1); CuniNPV, Culex nigripalpus nucleopolyhedrovirus (NP_203392.1); OrNV, Oryctes rhinoceros nudivirus (YP_002321398.1); KV, Kallithea virus (YP_009346005.1); NIENV, Nilaparvata lugens endogenous nudivirus (AHW98243.1); GbNV, Gryllus bimaculatus nudivirus (YP_001111268.1); HzNV-2, Helicoverpa zea nudivirus (YP_004956856.1); ToNV, Tipula oleracea nudivirus (YP_009116710.1); PmNV, Penaeus monodon nudivirus (YP_009051897.1); MdBV, Microplitis demolitor bracovirus (XP_008543854.1); CcBV, Cotesia congregate bracovirus (CAR82239.1). (B) Neighbor-joining phylogenetic analysis of 38K homologs performed by MEGA 7. ROP9, which belongs to the 38K/ROP9 family of the HAD superfamily, is encoded by Toxoplasma gondii (XP_002366872.1). The bootstrap scores of the nodes are shown.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>12913</offset><text>The HAD motifs of 38K are essential for nucleocapsid assembly.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>12976</offset><text>To investigate the function of the HAD motifs in 38K during the virus life cycle, four recombinant viruses, v38K:SM1, v38K:SM2, v38K:SM3, and v38K:SM4, were generated, in which the HAD motifs in 38K were individually mutated to alanine residues (Fig. 2A).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">zjv0091834970002.jpg</infon><infon key="id">F2</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>13232</offset><text>(A) Schematic diagram of the recombinant viruses used in this study. 38K-mutated viruses were constructed by mutating the amino acids of HAD motifs with alanines, and mutants of 38K as well as the polh and egfp genes were transposed into the mini-attTn7 locus of b38KKO individually. vP6.9:5E or vP6.9:5A was generated by changing the indicated amino acids of P6.9 to glutamic acids or alanines, respectively, and then the p6.9 mutant together with polh and egfp were transposed into bP6.9KO. (B and C) Expression of 38K or P6.9 in recombinant virus-transfected cells. Sf9 cells were transfected with bacmid DNA of v38K:SM1, v38K:SM2, v38K:SM3, v38K:SM4, or vGP64KO to examine the expression levels of modified 38K or wild-type 38K (left panels) or transfected with vAcWT, vP6.9:5A, vP6.9:5E, or vGP64KO to examine the expression levels of modified P6.9 or wild-type P6.9 (right panels). At 48 h p.t., the transfected cells were collected and subjected to SDS-PAGE for immunoblotting with the anti-38K polyclonal antibodies (B, left panel) or with the anti-P6.9 polyclonal antibodies (B, right panel). Actin was detected with an antiactin monoclonal antibody as a loading control. The protein expression levels were analyzed by Gel-Pro analyzer 4 and normalized to the expression levels of actin (C). The differences between the protein expression levels were analyzed by Student's t test with GraphPad Prism software. Bar heights represent the average from three independent experiments, and the error bars indicate the standard deviations. **, P &lt; 0.01.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>14788</offset><text>Sf9 cells transfected with bacmid DNA of the 38K mutant viruses or the vAcWT (WT AcMNPV vAcPH-GFP) were monitored by fluorescence microscopy, since all viruses could express the enhanced green fluorescence protein (egfp) gene. At 24 h posttransfection (p.t.), no obvious differences in the numbers of fluorescent cells were observed, indicating comparable transfection efficiencies among all the viruses. By 96 h p.t., most of the cells transfected with vAcWT bacmid DNA showed fluorescence, while the number of fluorescent cells transfected with v38K:SM2, v38K:SM3, or v38K:SM4 bacmid DNA did not increase from 24 to 96 h p.t. (Fig. 3A), indicating the inability of these viruses to spread the infection beyond the cells initially transfected. On the other hand, a slight increase in the number of fluorescent cells was observed for v38K:SM1 from 24 to 96 h p.t. (Fig. 3A), suggesting that limited infectious BVs were produced from the initially transfected cells. The ability of v38K:SM1 to produce infectious BV was analyzed by 50% tissue culture infective dose (TCID50) endpoint dilution assay using virus supernatants harvested from transfected cells at 96 h p.t. As shown in Fig. 3B, the total number of infectious BVs generated by v38K:SM1 was approximately 15,000-fold lower than that generated by vAcWT (P &lt; 0.01).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">zjv0091834970003.jpg</infon><infon key="id">F3</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>16112</offset><text>Analysis of virus replication and BV production in Sf9 cells. (A) Sf9 cells were transfected with 1 mug bacmids of the indicated recombinant viruses and monitored for infection by fluorescence microscopy as indicated by GFP expression. The top panels show cells transfected with bacmids at 24 h p.t., and the middle panels show the progression of virus infection at 96 h p.t. The bottom panels show viral plaques visualized at 96 h p.t. Arrowheads indicate the plaques formed by single cells. (B) Infectious BV production by vAcWT and v38K:SM1. Sf9 cells were transfected with bacmids of vAcWT or v38K:SM1. The supernatants of transfected cells were harvested at 96 h p.t., and the BV titers were determined by TCID50 endpoint dilution assay. Student's t test analysis of variance was carried out with GraphPad Prism software. Bar heights represent the average from three independent experiments, and the error bars indicate the standard deviations. (C) Plaque diameters in vAcWT- or v38K:SM1-transfected cells. A total of 60 plaques were measured in vAcWT- or v38K:SM1-transfected cells. Plaque size differences were analyzed by Student's t test with GraphPad Prism software. Bars indicate the medians for samples. **, P &lt; 0.01; ***, P &lt; 0.001.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17358</offset><text>Plaque assays were performed, and plaques were photographed at 96 h p.t. to further compare the spreading of virus to neighboring cells among these viruses. Plaques produced by v38K:SM2, v38K:SM3, and v38K:SM4 consisted of single cells (Fig. 3A), indicating that these viruses were unable to spread. Although larger plaques consisting of several cells were generated by v38K:SM1 (Fig. 3A), they were significantly smaller than those from vAcWT bacmid DNA-transfected cells (P &lt; 0.0001) (Fig. 3C).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>17855</offset><text>The expression of 38K in the 38K mutants in virus bacmid DNA-transfected cells was confirmed by immunoblotting with anti-38K antibodies, and representative immunoblots are shown in Fig. 2B (left panels). The quantitative results for protein expression levels are shown in Fig. 2C (left panel) and indicate that the expression of the modified 38K was at levels similar to those for the wild-type 38K in a gp64 knockout virus (vGP64KO) which lacks infectivity in insect cells and was used as a noninfectious control virus. Thus, the above results demonstrated that the conserved sequence motifs of the HAD superfamily in 38K play an important role in viral replication.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>18523</offset><text>The deletion of 38K from the AcMNPV genome resulted in no BV production and interruption of nucleocapsid assembly by producing capsid sheaths devoid of genomic DNA. To determine the effects of mutations in the HAD motifs of 38K on virion morphogenesis, thin sections of Sf9 cells transfected with bacmid DNA of vAcWT and 38K mutant viruses were analyzed via transmission electron microscopy (TEM). As expected, the formation of VS interspersed with rod-shaped electron-dense nucleocapsid (Fig. 4A) and ODV-containing polyhedra within the RZ (data not shown) was observed in vAcWT-transfected cells. In the cells transfected with v38K:SM1, although the VS was developed and several electron-dense nucleocapsids were observed (Fig. 4B), masses of electron-lucent tubular structures were present at the intrastromal space of the VS (Fig. 4B). ODV-embedding polyhedra were also observed in v38K:SM1-transfected cells (data not shown). On the other hand, the v38K:SM2-, v38K:SM3-, or v38K:SM4-transfected cells displayed a v38KKO-like pattern of virion morphogenesis, with development of the VS, formation of masses of electron-lucent tubular structures (Fig. 4C to E), and normal sizes of polyhedra without embedding of ODVs (data not shown). Even though v38K:SM1 produces some infectious BVs, the results from the TEM analysis indicated that all of the HAD motifs of 38K are essential for nucleocapsid assembly.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">zjv0091834970004.jpg</infon><infon key="id">F4</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>19932</offset><text>Mutation of HAD motifs in 38K affects nucleocapsid assembly. Transmission electron microscopy analysis of cells transfected with bacmids of vAcWT (A), v38K:SM1 (B), v38K:SM2 (C), v38K:SM3 (D), or v38K:SM4 (E) at 72 h p.t. is shown. (A) Electron-dense nucleocapsids are indicated by arrows. (B) Electron-dense nucleocapsids and electron-lucent tubules in the virogenic stroma (VS) are indicated by arrows and arrowheads, respectively. (C to E) Electron-lucent tubules in the VS are indicated by arrowheads. Scale bars represent 500 nm.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>20467</offset><text>38K mediates the dephosphorylation of P6.9.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>20511</offset><text>The baculovirus-encoded protamine-like protein P6.9 is composed predominantly of arginines (40%), serines/threonines (31%), tyrosines (13%), and glycines (9%) and is highly positively charged. In our previous study, 7 phosphorylated (no. 1 to 7) and 1 unphosphorylated (no. 0) P6.9 species resolved by AU-PAGE were observed by immunoblotting with protein samples from WT-resembling virus vPK1:FLAG-infected cells. Different species of P6.9 can be briefly classified into 3 groups: unphosphorylated species found in BVs (the no. 0 rung in AU-PAGE), hypophosphorylated species (rungs 1 to 4 in AU-PAGE) that may be phosphorylated by host kinases, and hyperphosphorylated species (rungs 5 to 7 in AU-PAGE) that are dependent on viral protein kinase PK1 phosphorylation. One phosphate group decreases the positive charge of P6.9 by one; therefore, each slower-migrating rung represents an increased phosphorylation occupancy. Since 38K deletion or mutations in the 38K HAD motifs resulted in interruption of nucleocapsid assembly and since the phosphorylation cycle of P6.9 is essential for condensing DNA into procapsids to form nucleocapsid, it is worth assessing the potential involvement of 38K in the phosphorylation cycle of P6.9 during nucleocapsid assembly.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>21773</offset><text>Sf9 cells transfected with bacmid DNA of v38KKO or vAcWT were sorted by flow cytometry at 48 h p.t. and subjected to AU-PAGE following immunoblotting with anti-P6.9 antibodies. As expected, only the unphosphorylated species of P6.9 was detected in BVs, and a ladder composed of 8 species of P6.9, including the unphosphorylated rung, was observed in vAcWT-transfected cells (Fig. 5A). However, 9 species of P6.9 were detected in v38KKO-transfected cells, with an additional lower-migrating rung (no. 8 in AU-PAGE) that represents a phosphorylation level higher than that of P6.9 species in vAcWT-transfected cells (Fig. 5A). This finding confirmed that some phosphorylation sites of P6.9 are unable to be dephosphorylated in the absence of 38K, suggesting that 38K mediates the dephosphorylation of P6.9 during the viral replication cycle.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">zjv0091834970005.jpg</infon><infon key="id">F5</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>22613</offset><text>38K mediates the dephosphorylation of P6.9. (A and B) Immunoblotting for P6.9 in bacmid DNA-transfected cells. Sf9 cells were transfected with bacmid DNA of vAcWT, v38KKO, SM1 (v38K:SM1), SM2 (v38K:SM2), SM3 (v38K:SM3), or SM4 (v38K:SM4). At 48 h p.t., the transfected cells were selected using flow cytometry and were subjected to AU-PAGE for immunoblotting with the anti-P6.9 polyclonal antibodies. BV, BVs purified from the supernatants of vAcWT-infected cells. Different species of P6.9 in v38KKO or 38K mutant virus bacmid DNA-transfected cells are indicated by numbers based on their mobility ratio in AU-PAGE. (C) PTM sites of P6.9 in v38KKO-transfected cells. All of the identified phosphorylation and methylation sites of P6.9 are shown in the schematic. The phosphorylated residues are indicated by capital letters; the methylated residues are indicated by lowercase letters. The phosphorylation sites of P6.9 dephosphorylated by 38K are marked by underlining. Circles represent the mono- and dimethylation sites.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>23637</offset><text>To further investigate whether the HAD motifs of 38K are involved in dephosphorylation of P6.9, the phosphorylation states of P6.9 in cells transfected with each 38K mutant virus bacmid DNA were analyzed. As shown in Fig. 5B, the more-hyperphosphorylated species of P6.9 (no. 8 in AU-PAGE) was also detected in cells transfected with each 38K mutant virus bacmid DNA, which was similar to the pattern detected in v38KKO-transfected cells. Although the P6.9 species in v38K:SM1-transfected cells has the same phosphorylation pattern as in v38KKO, the amount of the unphosphorylated species appeared to be increased in v38K:SM1-transfected cells compared to that with v38KKO or other 38K mutant viruses (Fig. 5B), which may be due to the production of limited infectious BVs. These results indicated that the HAD motifs of 38K are required for the dephosphorylation of P6.9 during virus replication.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>24535</offset><text>Five phosphorylation sites at the C terminus of P6.9 identified to be dephosphorylated by 38K.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>24630</offset><text>The phosphorylation sites of different P6.9 species were analyzed in Sf9 cells infected with WT-resembling virus vPK1:FLAG by MS in our previous study. A total of 22 residues, including 8 serines, 5 threonines, and 9 arginines, were determined to be phosphorylated in rungs 1 to 7 of P6.9 species separated by AU-PAGE, whereas none was identified in the BVs or no. 0 P6.9 species in AU-PAGE.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>25022</offset><text>To determine the specific phosphorylated residues that were dephosphorylated by 38K, the phosphorylated species of P6.9 in v38KKO bacmid DNA-transfected Sf9 cells were analyzed by MS utilizing both collision-induced dissociation and electron transfer dissociation fragmentation techniques, as previously described. The results showed that a total of 25 residues of P6.9 were phosphorylated in v38KKO bacmid DNA-transfected cells, among which 10 were serine residues (S9, S10, S17, S23, S24, S39, S41, S43, S44, and S49), 4 were threonine residues (T11, T13, T14, and T18), and 11 were arginine residues (R6, R7, R8, R19, R21, R22, R34, R38, R40, R42, and R47) (Fig. 5C and Table 1). In line with a previous study in which the phosphorylation sites of P6.9 in vPK1:FLAG-infected cells were determined, the phosphoRS probabilities of these sites are all above 75 (Table 1), and these phosphorylated sites were confirmed by manual validation based on site-determining ions in tandem MS (MS/MS) spectra, indicating that these sites were indeed phosphorylated. Therefore, by comparison with the previous results, 5 new phosphorylation sites (R34, R38, S39, R40, and S44) of P6.9 were revealed in v38KKO-transfected cells and were thought to be specifically dephosphorylated by 38K. However, 2 phosphorylation sites (T45 and R48) observed in vPK1:FLAG-infected cells previously were not detected in the current study, and the reason is unknown.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>26461</offset><text>P6.9 phosphorylation site mapping data</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Sequence of identified peptide&lt;xref ref-type=&quot;table-fn&quot; rid=&quot;T1F1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;italic&gt;a&lt;/italic&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/xref&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Site(s)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;PhosphoRS probability(ies)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRRRRSStGTtY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;T11, T14&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;86.8, 86.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RrSrSRSSTGrRSY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R38, R40, R47&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;99.9, 99.9, 99.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRSRSrSSTGRRSY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R42&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;100.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRRrrSSTGTTY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R7, R8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;99.2, 100.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRrRRSSTGTTY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;87.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRRRrSSTGTTY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;97.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GSTRRRrSSGY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;89.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GSTRRrrSSGY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R21, R22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;96.4, 99.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRRRRSStGTTY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;T11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;91.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRRRRSSTGtTY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;T13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;75.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRrRRSSTGTTY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;90.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRSRsrSSTGRRSY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;S41, R42&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;93.2, 93.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GSTrRRRSsGY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R19, S24&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;80.3, 82.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GSTRRRRssGYRRRPGRPRTY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;S23, S24&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98.9, 98.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRRRrSSTGTTY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;S9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;81.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRSRsRsSTGRRSY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;S41, S43&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;99.9, 99.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRRRRssTGTTY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;S9, S10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;100.0, 100.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GSTRRRRssGY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;S23, S24&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;97.8, 99.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRsRsRSsTGRRSY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;S39, S41, S44&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;100.0, 100.0, 99.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRRRRsStGTTY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;S9, T11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;95.9, 94.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRRRRSSTGtTY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;T13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;76.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GSTRRRrSSGY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;89.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRRRrSSTGTTY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;99.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GSTRRrrSSGY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R21, R22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;96.6, 99.9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRRrRSSTGTTY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;91.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GSTrRRrSSGY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R19, R22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;99.0, 95.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRRRRSsTGTTY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;S10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;85.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GSTRRRRsSGY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;S23&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;87.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GSTRRRRssGY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;S23, S24&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;99.6, 99.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRsRsRSsTGRRSY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;S39, S41, S44&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;100.0, 100.0, 94.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GSTRRRRSsGY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;S24&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;90.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRRRRSStGTTY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;T11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;99.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GStRRRRSSGY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;T18&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;100.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;GSTRRrRSSGYRRRPGRPrTY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R21, R34&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;96.4, 83.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RrsrSRSSTGRRSY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;R38, S39, R40&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;88.9, 99.5, 82.7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;RRSRSRsSTGRRsY&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;S43, S49&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;99.9, 89.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>26500</offset><text>Sequence of identified peptidea	Site(s)	PhosphoRS probability(ies)	 	RRRRRSStGTtY	T11, T14	86.8, 86.8	 	RrSrSRSSTGrRSY	R38, R40, R47	99.9, 99.9, 99.9	 	RRSRSrSSTGRRSY	R42	100.0	 	RRRrrSSTGTTY	R7, R8	99.2, 100.0	 	RRrRRSSTGTTY	R6	87.2	 	RRRRrSSTGTTY	R8	97.7	 	GSTRRRrSSGY	R22	89.6	 	GSTRRrrSSGY	R21, R22	96.4, 99.8	 	RRRRRSStGTTY	T11	91.5	 	RRRRRSSTGtTY	T13	75.7	 	RRrRRSSTGTTY	R7	90.5	 	RRSRsrSSTGRRSY	S41, R42	93.2, 93.2	 	GSTrRRRSsGY	R19, S24	80.3, 82.7	 	GSTRRRRssGYRRRPGRPRTY	S23, S24	98.9, 98.9	 	RRRRrSSTGTTY	S9	81.5	 	RRSRsRsSTGRRSY	S41, S43	99.9, 99.9	 	RRRRRssTGTTY	S9, S10	100.0, 100.0	 	GSTRRRRssGY	S23, S24	97.8, 99.3	 	RRsRsRSsTGRRSY	S39, S41, S44	100.0, 100.0, 99.6	 	RRRRRsStGTTY	S9, T11	95.9, 94.6	 	RRRRRSSTGtTY	T13	76.3	 	GSTRRRrSSGY	R22	89.5	 	RRRRrSSTGTTY	R8	99.4	 	GSTRRrrSSGY	R21, R22	96.6, 99.9	 	RRRrRSSTGTTY	R7	91.8	 	GSTrRRrSSGY	R19, R22	99.0, 95.0	 	RRRRRSsTGTTY	S10	85.7	 	GSTRRRRsSGY	S23	87.5	 	GSTRRRRssGY	S23, S24	99.6, 99.8	 	RRsRsRSsTGRRSY	S39, S41, S44	100.0, 100.0, 94.3	 	GSTRRRRSsGY	S24	90.8	 	RRRRRSStGTTY	T11	99.4	 	GStRRRRSSGY	T18	100.0	 	GSTRRrRSSGYRRRPGRPrTY	R21, R34	96.4, 83.1	 	RrsrSRSSTGRRSY	R38, S39, R40	88.9, 99.5, 82.7	 	RRSRSRsSTGRRsY	S43, S49	99.9, 89.5	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T1.xml</infon><infon key="id">T1</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_footnote</infon><offset>27709</offset><text>The phosphorylated residues are indicated by lowercase letters.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>27773</offset><text>In addition to the phosphorylation modifications, the presence of other PTMs of P6.9 was also investigated in raw MS data obtained from the v38KKO-transfected cells. No acetylated sites were detected in the P6.9 species, which is consistent with a previous study. Many methylated sites were identified, as before, including monomethylation and dimethylation: only R6 and R8 were monomethylated; R27, R28, R29, R32, and R34 were dimethylated; and R5, R42, R47, R48, R51, and R53 showed both states (Fig. 5C).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>28281</offset><text>A phosphorylation-mimic mutant of P6.9 impairs nucleocapsid assembly.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>28351</offset><text>To investigate the role of dephosphorylation of P6.9 mediated by 38K in the virus life cycle, a phosphorylation-mimic mutant virus (vP6.9:5E) and a phosphorylation-deficient mutant virus (vP6.9:5A) were constructed, as described in Materials and Methods. The phosphorylation sites in P6.9 that were postulated to be dephosphorylated by 38K were mutated to glutamic acids in vP6.9:5E to mimic the phosphorylation of P6.9 or were mutated to alanines in vP6.9:5A to simulate the dephosphorylation of P6.9 (Fig. 2A).</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>28864</offset><text>The expression of the mutated P6.9 was confirmed by immunoblotting using protein samples prepared from vP6.9:5E or vP6.9:5A bacmid DNA-transfected cells (Fig. 2B, right panels), and the expression levels of the mutated P6.9 in vP6.9:5A- or vP6.9:5E-transfected cells were compared with those of a wild-type P6.9 in vAcWT or vGP64KO, respectively (Fig. 2C, right panel). The results indicated that the expression levels of the mutated P6.9 are at levels similar to those of the wild-type P6.9 in their respective control virus (Fig. 2C, right panel). Because no infectious virions were produced by vP6.9:5E and vGP64KO, the expression levels of P6.9 in vP6.9:5E- or vGP64KO-transfected cells are significantly lower than those in vP6.9:5A- or vAcWT-transfected cells (Fig. 2C, right panel). Transfection of bacmid DNA of the recombinant viruses in Sf9 cells was monitored by microscopy and analyzed by virus growth curve analyses and plaque assays. Replication of vP6.9:5E in the cells was similar to that of v38KKO, including single-cell infection, as indicated by eGFP expression examined by fluorescence microscopy, OB formation in the infected cells as observed under light microscopy, and undetectable infectious BV production as shown by virus growth curve analysis (Fig. 6A and B). For the cells transfected with vAcWT or vP6.9:5A bacmid DNA, the number of fluorescent cells increased dramatically from 24 to 96 h p.t., and OBs were observed in many infected cells, indicating that complete virus replication cycles occurred (Fig. 6A). Virus growth curve analyses showed that the BV titer of vP6.9:5A at 96 h postinfection was 10-fold lower than that of vAcWT at a multiplicity of infection (MOI) of 5 (P &lt; 0.01) and 25-fold lower at an MOI of 0.01 (P &lt; 0.01) (Fig. 6B). Virus plaques produced by vP6.9:5E consisted of single cells, whereas plaques from vAcWT or vP6.9:5A bacmid DNA-transfected cells contained a number of fluorescent cells (data not shown). A relative quantitative analysis of the sizes of virus plaques showed that plaques produced by vP6.9:5A were significantly smaller than those produced by vAcWT (P &lt; 0.01) (Fig. 6C).</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">zjv0091834970006.jpg</infon><infon key="id">F6</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>31011</offset><text>A phosphorylation-mimic mutant of P6.9 impairs virus replication. (A) Sf9 cells were transfected with vAcWT, vP6.9:5E (phosphorylation-mimic mutant), or vP6.9:5A (phosphorylation-deficient mutant) bacmid DNA. At the indicated time points, cells were visualized by fluorescence microscopy for infection. Light microscopy images show the formation of OBs in the transfected cells at 96 h p.t. (B) Virus growth curves. Sf9 cells were infected with vAcWT or vP6.9:5A at an MOI of 0.01 (i) or 5 (ii) TCID50/cell or all the supernatants from vP6.9:5E-transfected cells at 96 h p.t. At the indicated time points, BV titers were determined by TCID50 endpoint dilution assays. (C) Plaque diameters in vAcWT- or vP6.9:5A-infected cells. A total of 40 plaques were measured in vAcWT- or vP6.9:5A-infected cells. Plaque size differences were analyzed by Student's t test with GraphPad Prism software. Bars indicate the medians for samples. **, P &lt; 0.01.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">RESULTS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>31953</offset><text>To assess the effects of mutations in P6.9 on viral nucleocapsid assembly, thin sections of cells transfected with bacmid DNA were analyzed by TEM. The vP6.9:5A-transfected cells showed results similar to those with vAcWT-transfected cells (Fig. 7A and D), including the presence of VS containing rod-shaped electron-dense nucleocapsids (Fig. 7B) and enveloped ODVs containing multiple nucleocapsids within the RZ or embedded in polyhedra (Fig. 7E). In contrast, aberrant capsids or electron-lucent tubular structures were observed at the intrastromal space of the VS and within the RZ of cells transfected with vP6.9:5E (Fig. 7C and F). These results revealed that the phosphomimetic mutation of P6.9 impaired the assembly of nucleocapsids.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">zjv0091834970007.jpg</infon><infon key="id">F7</infon><infon key="section_type">FIG</infon><infon key="type">fig_caption</infon><offset>32695</offset><text>A phosphorylation-mimic mutant of P6.9 interrupts nucleocapsid assembly. vAcWT-transfected (A and D), vP6.9:5A-transfected (B and E), or vP6.9:5E-transfected (C and F) cells at 72 h p.t. are shown. (A and B) Rod-shaped electron-dense nucleocapsids are observed in the VS. (D and E) ODVs and polyhedra containing ODVs are found within the RZ. (C and F) Abnormally long, electron-lucent tubules (indicated by arrows) can be found in the VS (C) and in the RZ (F). VS, virogenic stroma. P, polyhedra. RZ, ring zone. nm, nuclear membrane. The bars represent 500 nm.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>33256</offset><text>DISCUSSION</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>33267</offset><text>Viral genomes are condensed and packaged into capsids by multiple mechanisms during encapsidation. Essential to this process is neutralization of the negative electrostatic charge on the phosphate groups of the nucleotide backbone by positively charged ions, such as divalent cations or other small basic cationic proteins. Baculovirus encodes a protamine-like small basic protein, P6.9, which is rich in arginine (40%) and serine/threonine (31%) residues. Evidence indicates that P6.9 is prevented from binding to DNA as a result of phosphorylation modification of arginine and serine residues. During viral assembly, P6.9 is dephosphorylated for neutralization of viral DNA and condensing DNA into the viral capsid. A previous study showed that multiple phosphorylation species of P6.9 were detected in virus-infected cells, but only the unphosphorylated species was presented in BVs, indicating that P6.9 undergoes phosphorylation and dephosphorylation cycles during virus replication. However, phosphatases of the virus or host that are responsible for the dephosphorylation of P6.9 during nucleocapsid assembly have not yet been determined. Here, our data suggest that baculovirus 38K may mediate dephosphorylation at 5 specific sites (R34, R38, S39, R40, and S44) at the C terminus of P6.9 and that dephosphorylation of these sites is essential for packaging of genomes in to capsids.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>34658</offset><text>38K is one of the 38 core genes of baculovirus, and its deletion results in interruption of viral genome encapsidation. Evolutionary genomics analysis showed that 38K belongs to the HAD superfamily, which is characterized by HAD motifs. Our current study confirmed that the HAD motifs of 38K were important for nucleocapsid assembly, since mutation of any motif resulted in production of abnormal electron-lucent tubular structures devoid of DNA content in virus-transfected cells (Fig. 4). Although these results imply that 38K may function as a viral phosphatase and that the enzyme activity may participate in nucleocapsid assembly, in vitro experiments to detect the phosphatase activity using purified 38K protein were unsuccessful (data not shown), suggesting that appropriate substrates or experimental conditions are critical. Among the members of the HAD superfamily, HAD motifs II and III contribute to the stability of the reaction intermediates of the hydrolysis reaction, and motif IV along with motif I is required for coordinating a magnesium ion in the active site. The mutations of these motifs in MDP-1, phosphoserine phosphatase (PSPase), and ATPase resulted in a loss of activity. Hence, the mutation of HAD motifs in 38K might alter its enzymatic activity and result in functional loss of 38K. Although a few nucleocapsids with DNA content were detected (Fig. 4B), and infectious BVs were produced (Fig. 3) in motif I-mutated virus bacmid DNA-transfected cells, the nucleocapsid assembly was severely impaired, and the BV production was 15,000-fold lower than that of the control virus. We speculate that the active center of 38K, which should have resided in motif I, may have partially been replaced by another conserved amino acid during evolution. 38K molecules have been shown to interact with each other as homo-oligomers, which suggests that 38K may function as a homodimer, unlike other HAD members.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>36587</offset><text>As P6.9 undergoes phosphorylation-dephosphorylation cycling during nucleocapsid assembly, the potential involvement of 38K in regulating the dephosphorylation of P6.9 was investigated in this study. The deletion of 38K or the mutation of the HAD motifs in 38K resulted in the production of a more phosphorylated species of P6.9 (no. 8 in AU-PAGE), as detected by AU-PAGE (Fig. 5A and B). The phosphorylation sites of P6.9 that are dephosphorylated by 38K were then determined by MS. Compared to the phosphorylation sites detected in the cells infected with the WT-resembling virus, five new sites (R34, R38, S39, R40, and S44) were identified (Fig. 5C) in v38KKO-transfected cells and thus were considered to be the sites mediated by 38K. The possible structure of P6.9 was predicted by using the online tool I-IASSER for protein and function predictions (https://zhanglab.ccmb.med.umich.edu/I-TASSER/), and the result showed that the R38, S39, R40, and S44 sites of P6.9 are clustered and the R34, R38, R40, and S44 sites are on the surface of P6.9 (data not shown). The spatial distribution of these sites possibly makes them accessible to 38K. However, these sites have a low degree of conservation in the P6.9 homologs among other baculoviruses. In addition, there might be other phosphorylation sites of P6.9 in the cells infected with the WT-resembling virus that are dephosphorylated by 38K and may still be present in the v38KKO-transfected cells, but these sites were unable to be detected by this method; thus, the dephosphorylation sites mediated by 38K may include more than the 5 sites identified in the current study. Meanwhile, the HAD motifs in 38K are involved in P6.9 dephosphorylation, suggesting that other phosphatases from the haloacid dehalogenase superfamily which process the HAD motifs may participate in the dephosphorylation of P6.9. However, the 38K family, which might have arisen from the MDP-1/FkbH family, is much smaller and shows a very unusual phyletic pattern that is found only in viruses, suggesting that phosphorylation of P6.9 at these 5 sites might be exclusively dephosphorylated by viral 38K. On the other hand, the unphosphorylated species of P6.9 present in cells transfected with 38K-deleted or -mutated virus bacmid DNA (Fig. 5A and B) indicated that other phosphatases take part in the regulation of dephosphorylation of other sites in P6.9. In addition, both 38K and p6.9 are viral late genes. Their transcripts were both expressed from 12 h postinfection. Although 38K does not contain a nuclear localization signal by prediction, it localized to the nuclei of transfected cells and localized mainly to the center of the nucleus in the late phase during virus infection. On the other hand, the majority of the P6.9 localized near the inner nuclear membrane, whereas a lower concentration of P6.9 was observed in the VS. Therefore, dephosphorylation of P6.9 mediated by 38K might take place in the nucleus during virus infection. Even though 38K mediates the dephosphorylation of P6.9, attempts to detect the interaction between 38K and P6.9 by yeast two-hybrid experiments and coimmunoprecipitation assays (data not shown) were unsuccessful. We speculate that the interaction between 38K and P6.9 is transient and thus difficult to be detected.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>39883</offset><text>Three of the 5 phosphorylation sites (R38, S39, and R40) dephosphorylated by 38K are in a 3-arginine-serine (RS) repeat region (38RSRSRS43) of P6.9 (Fig. 5C). These sites may be phosphorylated by host kinases, as the RS repeats in protamine are potential phosphorylation targets of arginine/serine protein-specific kinase 1 and topoisomerase I. The phosphorylation-deficient mutant virus of P6.9 (vP6.9:5A) produced fewer infectious BVs and smaller plaques (Fig. 6B and C), which may have resulted from fewer phosphate groups added to P6.9. Evidence suggests that newly synthesized P6.9 is transiently phosphorylated in virus-infected cells prior to participation in nucleocapsid assembly; thus, the phosphorylation of the sites mutated to alanines in vP6.9:5A is beneficial for virus replication. Therefore, nonphosphorylation of these sites in vP6.9:5A resulted in reduced BV production. Similarly, in a previous study in which other phosphorylation sites of P6.9 were mutated to alanines, the viral infectivity was severely impaired. On the other hand, the phosphorylation-mimic mutant virus (vP6.9:5E) led to a failure of viral DNA encapsidation (Fig. 7). PTMs regulate protein conformation as well as protein-protein interactions, and the phosphorylation of protamine has been suggested to disturb intraprotamine and interprotamine interactions. Therefore, the phosphorylation-mimic mutant of P6.9 may disrupt the tightness of P6.9 complexes and interfere with the interaction of P6.9 with DNA due to electrostatic repulsion, resulting in unsuccessful condensation of viral DNA. Moreover, a previous study showed that the dephosphorylation of P6.9, at least at the C terminus (aa 29 to 55), occurred at the surface of the electron-dense stoma matte of the VS and at what appeared to be nucleocapsids undergoing assembly, indicating that the C terminus of P6.9 undergoes dephosphorylation during nucleocapsid assembly. Thus, the inability to dephosphorylate the phosphorylation sites located at the C terminus of P6.9, which was the case for the phosphorylation-mimic mutant in the present study, resulted in unsuccessful nucleocapsid assembly.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>42032</offset><text>Baculoviruses are not the only double-stranded DNA (dsDNA) viruses that use protamine-like proteins to condense their genome. WSSV encodes a similar protein named VP15, which is major nucleocapsid protein and has been shown to bind both AcMNPV and WSSV DNAs. The phosphorylation of P6.9 in baculovirus may be important for the decondensation and ejection of the viral genome into the cell nucleus, whereas the phosphorylated species of VP15 have not been found yet. This could imply that VP15 may use a different mechanism for releasing DNA. The P64 protein of Spodoptera frugiperda ascovirus 1a (SfAV1a) contains 14 copies of a highly basic, tandemly repeated motif rich in arginine and serine residues at its C terminus. It has been shown that P64 binds SfAV1a DNA and is incorporated into the SfAV1a DNA core during virion assembly, supporting the hypothesis that P64 is involved in packaging viral DNA. Whether nascent P64 is phosphorylated is unknown, but it is unphosphorylated in the mature virion. Adenoviruses also encode a highly basic protein called protein VII that binds and condenses DNA. In addition, protein VII has PTMs, including phosphorylation, that contribute to its chromatin localization and hinder chromatin association of host proteins, leading to abrogated immune responses. P6.9 was located primarily within the region of marginalized host chromatin induced by baculovirus infection, suggesting that P6.9 may adopt a strategy similar to that of protein VII to alter host chromatin dynamics. Taken together, the data indicate that although basic proteins encoded by different viruses can be either phosphorylated or unphosphorylated, only unphosphorylated species of basic proteins are incorporated into mature virions, where they presumably assist in neutralizing negative electrostatic charges conferred by phosphate groups in DNA. Therefore, for dsDNA viruses using basic proteins to condense and package DNA into nucleocapsids, it is necessary that phosphorylated basic proteins, if any, be dephosphorylated during nucleocapsid assembly.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>44100</offset><text>It should be noted that in addition to mediating the dephosphorylation of P6.9, 38K may participate in nucleocapsid assembly in other ways. 38K is a nucleocapsid-associated protein and interacts with other capsid proteins, such as VP39, VP1054, and VP80. It is possible that these interactions may be required for nucleocapsid assembly, and the deletion or mutation of 38K may disrupt these interactions and thus result in a failure of nucleocapsid assembly. For example, the nucleocapsid assembly was interrupted and the distribution of 38K was intensively changed with the deletion of the gene encoding 38K-interacting protein VP1054; thus, the function of 38K may be abolished due to its aberrant localization.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">DISCUSS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>44814</offset><text>In summary, our current study demonstrated that the viral nucleocapsid-associated protein 38K mediates the dephosphorylation of 5 specific residues at the C terminus of P6.9. The phosphorylation of these sites promotes virus replication, while their dephosphorylation is essential for nucleocapsid assembly in the AcMNPV life cycle. This suggests, at least partially, a novel function and mechanism of 38K in the virus life cycle. To further elucidate how phosphorylation and dephosphorylation cycles of P6.9 are regulated to facilitate genome ejection and encapsidation, further experimentation is needed to identify other phosphatases or kinases that act on P6.9.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_1</infon><offset>45480</offset><text>MATERIALS AND METHODS</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>45502</offset><text>Cells and viruses.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>45521</offset><text>The Sf9 (Spodoptera frugiperda IPLB-Sf21-AE clonal isolate 9) insect cells were cultured at 27 C in Grace's medium (Invitrogen) supplemented with 10% fetal bovine serum, 100 mug/ml penicillin, and 30 mug/ml streptomycin. The AcMNPV 38K-knockout bacmid vAc38K-KO (defined as b38KKO in the present study), the 38K-knockout virus with polyhedrin and egfp genes vAc38K-KO-PH-GFP (defined as v38KKO in the present study), and a control virus resembling the WT AcMNPV vAcPH-GFP (defined as vAcWT in the present study) were constructed in our previous study. The p6.9-knockout recombinant bacmid bP6.9KO was also constructed previously by Liu et al..</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>46166</offset><text>Bioinformatics analyses.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>46191</offset><text>The conserved domains in AcMNPV 38K were predicted from the NCBI Conserved Domain Search database (https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/Structure/cdd/wrpsb.cgi), and the homologs of 38K were searched against the NCBI protein database (https://blast.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/Blast.cgi?PROGRAM=blastp&amp;PAGE_TYPE=BlastSearch&amp;LINK_LOC=blasthome) with the BLAST algorithm. Multiple-sequence alignments of 38K were carried out with Clustal X with default settings and were edited with GeneDoc. The 38K homologs selected for sequence alignments (Fig. 1A) from the family Baculoviridae were as follows: the group I alphabaculoviruses AcMNPV, Bombyx mori NPV, and Orgyia pseudotsugata MNPV; the group II alphabaculoviruses Agrotis segetum NPV, Spodoptera exigua MNPV, and Lymantria dispar MNP; the betabaculoviruses Agrotis segetum granulovirus (GV), Cydia pomonella GV, and Spodoptera litura GV; the deltabaculovirus Culex nigripalpus NPV; and the gammabaculoviruses Neodiprion abietis NPV, Neodiprion lecontei NPV, and Neodiprion sertifer NPV. In addition, 38K homologs from the families Nudiviridae and Polydnaviridae were also selected for multiple-sequence alignment, including the family Nudiviridae viruses Oryctes rhinoceros nudivirus, Kallithea virus, Nilaparvata lugens endogenous nudivirus, Gryllus bimaculatus nudivirus, Helicoverpa zea nudivirus, Tipula oleracea nudivirus, and Penaeus monodon nudivirus and the family Polydnaviridae viruses Microplitis demolitor bracovirus and Cotesia congregate bracovirus.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>47688</offset><text>Construction of recombinant viruses.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>47725</offset><text>To dissect the function of 38K in nucleocapsid assembly, the four highly conserved motifs of the HAD superfamily in 38K, i.e., D140xD142 motif I, S177 motif II, K251 motif III, and D275D276 motif IV, were mutated to A140xA142, A177, A251, and A275A276 (Fig. 2A) individually by a previously described method. To this end, a 1,522-bp fragment containing the WT 38K gene with its own promoter and poly(A) signal was first PCR amplified using primers Ac9855 and Ac98310 and was ligated to the pMD18-T vector (TaKaRa) using PstI and XbaI sites to generate T-38KPOA2. Four sets of primers (all primers used in this study are presented in Table 2) were then used to construct the recombinant plasmids T-38KSM1, T-38KSM2, T-38KSM3, and T-38KSM4 using T-38KPOA2 as a template. Primers 98517Ft, 98518Fs, 98313Rt, and 98314Rs were used to introduce A140xA142 in 38K; primers 98519Ft, 98520Fs, 98315Rt, and 98316Rs were used to introduce A177 in 38K; primers 98521Ft, 98522Fs, 98317Rt, and 98318Rs were used to introduce A251 in 38K; and primers 98523Ft, 98524Fs, 98319Rt, and 98320Rs were used to introduce A275A276 in 38K. The 38KSM1, 38KSM2, 38KSM3, and 38KSM4 fragments were released from the T vectors by PstI/XbaI digestion and were ligated to pFB1-PH-GFP to generate donor plasmids pFB-38KSM1-PG, pFB-38KSM2-PG, pFB-38KSM3-PG, and pFB-38KSM4-PG, respectively. The donor plasmids were then transformed into Escherichia coli DH10B cells containing helper plasmid pMON7124 and the 38K-knockout bacmid b38KKO to generate 38K site-mutated viruses v38K:SM1, v38K:SM2, v38K:SM3, and v38K:SM4, respectively.</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T2.xml</infon><infon key="id">T2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table_caption</infon><offset>49321</offset><text>Primers used in this study</text></passage><passage><infon key="file">T2.xml</infon><infon key="id">T2</infon><infon key="section_type">TABLE</infon><infon key="type">table</infon><infon key="xml">&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;table frame=&quot;hsides&quot; rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;&lt;colgroup span=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;col align=&quot;left&quot; span=&quot;1&quot;/&gt;&lt;/colgroup&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;bottom&quot;&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Primer&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&quot;left&quot; rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;Sequence&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98517Ft&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5'-GTGTTTGCATTGGCAAGCACTCTCATAACCGAAGAGGAGC-3'&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98518Fs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5'-ACTCTCATAACCGAAGAGGAGC-3'&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98313Rt&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5'-GCTTGCCAATGCAAACACGACCACGTGCGGAAATCCCCAC-3'&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98314Rs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5'-GACCACGTGCGGAAATCCCCAC-3'&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98519Ft&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5'-TTGTGGGCATATGGCAGTAGAGATCATGTAGCACACTCGA-3'&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98520Fs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5'-AGAGATCATGTAGCACACTCGA-3'&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98315Rt&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5'-ACTGCCATATGCCCACAAGACTAAAACGCAACCCATCTCG-3'&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98316Rs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5'-GACTAAAACGCAACCCATCTCG-3'&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98521Ft&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5'-ATACCCGCATCGCCAAAAATTGTAATTAAATATTTGAGCG-3'&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98522Fs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5'-ATTGTAATTAAATATTTGAGCG-3'&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98317Rt&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5'-TTTTGGCGATGCGGGTATATTGTTGTCGGATCGATGATTG-3'&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98318Rs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5'-ATTGTTGTCGGATCGATGATTG-3'&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98523Ft&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5'-CTTGCCGCAGCACTGCCAACTAATAACTACGCGTACGATT-3'&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98524Fs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5'-ACTAATAACTACGCGTACGATT-3'&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98319Rt&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5'-TGGCAGTGCTGCGACAAGTGTGATCGACTTGAAAAAGTTT-3'&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;98320Rs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td rowspan=&quot;1&quot; colspan=&quot;1&quot;&gt;5'-TGTGATCGACTTGAAAAAGTTT-3'&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
</infon><offset>49348</offset><text>Primer	Sequence	 	98517Ft	5'-GTGTTTGCATTGGCAAGCACTCTCATAACCGAAGAGGAGC-3'	 	98518Fs	5'-ACTCTCATAACCGAAGAGGAGC-3'	 	98313Rt	5'-GCTTGCCAATGCAAACACGACCACGTGCGGAAATCCCCAC-3'	 	98314Rs	5'-GACCACGTGCGGAAATCCCCAC-3'	 	98519Ft	5'-TTGTGGGCATATGGCAGTAGAGATCATGTAGCACACTCGA-3'	 	98520Fs	5'-AGAGATCATGTAGCACACTCGA-3'	 	98315Rt	5'-ACTGCCATATGCCCACAAGACTAAAACGCAACCCATCTCG-3'	 	98316Rs	5'-GACTAAAACGCAACCCATCTCG-3'	 	98521Ft	5'-ATACCCGCATCGCCAAAAATTGTAATTAAATATTTGAGCG-3'	 	98522Fs	5'-ATTGTAATTAAATATTTGAGCG-3'	 	98317Rt	5'-TTTTGGCGATGCGGGTATATTGTTGTCGGATCGATGATTG-3'	 	98318Rs	5'-ATTGTTGTCGGATCGATGATTG-3'	 	98523Ft	5'-CTTGCCGCAGCACTGCCAACTAATAACTACGCGTACGATT-3'	 	98524Fs	5'-ACTAATAACTACGCGTACGATT-3'	 	98319Rt	5'-TGGCAGTGCTGCGACAAGTGTGATCGACTTGAAAAAGTTT-3'	 	98320Rs	5'-TGTGATCGACTTGAAAAAGTTT-3'	 	</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>50199</offset><text>To investigate the role of the phosphorylation cycle of P6.9 in nucleocapsid assembly, a phosphorylation-deficient mutant virus (vP6.9:5A) and a phosphorylation-mimic mutant virus (vP6.9:5E) were constructed. In brief, the p6.9 mutants with 5 residues (arginines at position 32, 38, and 40 and serines at position 39 and 44) mutated to alanines (A32A38A39A40A44) or glutamic acids (E32E38E39E40E44) were generated by total gene synthesis technology and then cloned into plasmid pUC19 (Ruibiotech). The mutants of p6.9 were cloned into pUC18-Pro-SV40, which contains the native promoter of p6.9, to generate pUC18-Pro-P6.9:5A-SV40 or pUC18-Pro-P6.9:5E-SV40. Pro-P6.9:5A-SV40 or Pro-P6.9:5E-SV40 was released from the plasmid described above and inserted into pFB1-PH-GFP to generate the donor plasmid pFB-P6.9:5A-PG or pFB-P6.9:5E-PG. Donor plasmid pFB-P6.9:5A-PG or pFB-P6.9:5E-PG then was transformed into DH10B cells containing pMON7124 and the p6.9-knockout bacmid bP6.9KO to generate the recombinant virus vP6.9:5A or vP6.9:5E.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>51231</offset><text>All of the constructs were confirmed by PCR analysis and DNA sequencing. Bacmid DNAs of recombinant viruses were electroporated into DH10B cells and screened for tetracycline sensitivity to remove the helper plasmid. Extrapure bacmid DNAs were then extracted and purified with the Large-Construct kit (Qiagen) and quantified by optical density measurement.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>51588</offset><text>Viral growth curve analyses and plaque assay.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>51634</offset><text>Bacmid DNA transfection and virus infection were performed as previously described. Specifically, Sf9 cells (1.0 x 106 cells/35-mm-diameter dish) were transfected with 1 mug bacmid DNAs of recombinant viruses using Lipofectin (Invitrogen) or infected with viruses at an MOI of 5 or 0.01. The viral inocula were allowed to be adsorbed by the cells for 5 h upon transfection or 1 h upon infection at 27 C and were then replaced with fresh medium. Time zero was defined as the time when fresh medium was added. The supernatants of transfected or infected cells were harvested at the indicated time points, and the titers were determined by TCID50 endpoint dilution assay on Sf9 cells.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>52318</offset><text>Plaque assays were performed as previously described. In brief, a total of 2.0 x 106 cells in a monolayer were transfected separately with 0.01 mug bacmid DNA of recombinant viruses. At 120 h p.t., plaques were photographed, and the sizes of plaques were measured.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>52584</offset><text>TEM analysis.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>52598</offset><text>Sf9 cells (1.0 x 106) transfected with bacmid DNAs of recombinant viruses were harvested at 72 h p.t. and pelleted at 2,000 x g for 10 min. The cells were subjected to TEM as previously described. Ultrathin sections were observed with a JEM 1400 transmission electron microscope at an accelerating voltage of 120 kV.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>52917</offset><text>Flow cytometry.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>52933</offset><text>Sf9 cells transfected with bacmid DNA or infected with recombinant viruses were harvested at 48 h after transfection or infection. The cells were washed twice with phosphate-buffered saline (PBS) and pelleted by centrifugation at 1,000 x g for 10 min. The supernatants were removed, and the cells were resuspended with PBS at approximately 1.0 x 107 cells/ml. The transfected or infected cells were selected using flow cytometry (MoFlo XDP; Beckman Coulter, USA) based on green fluorescence, as previously described.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>53452</offset><text>AU-PAGE.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>53461</offset><text>To separate the different phosphorylated species of P6.9, AU-PAGE was performed as previously described. For BV samples, supernatants collected from vAcWT-infected Sf9 cells were purified by sucrose gradient centrifugation and resuspended in 0.1 M Tris-EDTA. The cells selected by flow cytometry or the purified BVs were denatured with AU gel sample buffer and were resolved by AU-15% PAGE.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>53852</offset><text>Immunoblotting.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>53868</offset><text>To detect the phosphorylation pattern of P6.9, total proteins resolved by AU-PAGE were transferred onto a 0.22-mum polyvinylidene fluoride membrane (Millipore) and immunoblotted with anti-P6.9 antibodies as described by Li et al.. To detect the expression of 38K or P6.9 in recombinant virus-transfected cells, the pelleted cells were resuspended in PBS with an equal volume of 2x protein sample buffer (0.25 M Tris-HCl [pH 6.8], 4% sodium dodecyl sulfate, 20% glycerol, 10% 2-mercaptoethanol, 0.02% bromophenol blue) and boiled at 100 C for 10 min. The samples were resolved by SDS-PAGE and transferred onto a 0.22-mum polyvinylidene fluoride membrane for immunoblotting with anti-38K polyclonal antibodies (1:500), anti-P6.9 polyclonal antibodies (1:1,000), or antiactin monoclonal antibodies (1:2,000; Abmart) and then quantified with a Gel-Pro analyzer 4. Three independent experiments were performed with actin as an internal reference protein.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">title_2</infon><offset>54820</offset><text>MS.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>54824</offset><text>To determine the phosphorylation sites of P6.9 in v38KKO bacmid DNA-transfected cells, P6.9 phosphorylated species were separated by AU-15% PAGE as described above and stained with Coomassie brilliant blue (Sigma). The preparation of MS samples was adopted from a previous study with modifications. In brief, the protein bands of phosphorylated P6.9 were excised from the gel and were subjected to in-gel digestion with chymotrypsin at a final concentration of 0.05 mug/mul (MS grade; Thermo Scientific) overnight at 37 C as previously described but without the reduction and alkylation steps. Peptides extracted from each digested species were pooled, desalted, and purified with Pierce graphite spin columns (Thermo Scientific). The PTMs of these peptides were determined with a hybrid linear ion trap-Orbitrap mass spectrometer (LTQ Orbitrap Elite; Thermo Scientific), as described by Li et al..</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">METHODS</infon><infon key="type">paragraph</infon><offset>55724</offset><text>A database search was performed with Proteome Discoverer 1.3 (Thermo Scientific) using the SEQUEST program with the amino acid sequence of AcMNPV P6.9 with search parameters set as previously described. The phosphoRS algorithm was also employed to evaluate the accuracy of phosphorylation site localizations. For each phosphorylation site, a phosphoRS probability above 75 indicated that the site actually was phosphorylated; these phosphorylated sites were confirmed by manual validation based on the presence and intensity of site-determining ions in MS/MS spectra.</text></passage><passage><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><offset>56292</offset><text>REFERENCES</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">277</infon><infon key="lpage">297</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hayakawa;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ko;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Okano;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Seong;given-names:SI</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Goto;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Maeda;given-names:S</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1006/viro.1999.9894</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">10502508</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Virology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">262</infon><infon key="year">1999</infon><offset>56303</offset><text>Sequence analysis of the Xestia c-nigrum granulovirus genome</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">7023</infon><infon key="lpage">7035</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lauzon;given-names:HA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lucarotti;given-names:CJ</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Krell;given-names:PJ</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Feng;given-names:Q</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Retnakaran;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Arif;given-names:BM</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/JVI.78.13.7023-7035.2004</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">15194779</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">78</infon><infon key="year">2004</infon><offset>56364</offset><text>Sequence and organization of the Neodiprion lecontei nucleopolyhedrovirus genome</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">163</infon><infon key="lpage">173</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Herniou;given-names:EA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Arif;given-names:BM</infon><infon key="name_10">surname:Carstens;given-names:EB</infon><infon key="name_11">surname:Lefkowitz;given-names:EJ</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Becnel;given-names:JJ</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Blissard;given-names:GW</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Bonning;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Harrison Jehle;given-names:RJA</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Theilmann;given-names:DA</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Vlka;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:King;given-names:AMQ</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Adams;given-names:MJ</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Virus taxonomy</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>56445</offset><text>Family Baculoviridae</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">147</infon><infon key="lpage">164</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Zanotto;given-names:PM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kessing;given-names:BD</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Maruniak;given-names:JE</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1006/jipa.1993.1090</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J invertebrate pathology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">62</infon><infon key="year">1993</infon><offset>56466</offset><text>Phylogenetic interrelationships among baculoviruses: evolutionary rates and host associations</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">586</infon><infon key="lpage">605</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Ayres;given-names:MD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Howard;given-names:SC</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kuzio;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Lopez-Ferber;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Possee;given-names:RD</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1006/viro.1994.1380</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8030224</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Virology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">202</infon><infon key="year">1994</infon><offset>56560</offset><text>The complete DNA sequence of Autographa californica nuclear polyhedrosis virus</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:Rohrmann;given-names:GF</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">National Library of Medicine</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">2013</infon><offset>56639</offset><text>Baculovirus molecular biology</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">99</infon><infon key="lpage">165</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Slack;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Arif;given-names:BM</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/S0065-3527(06)69003-9</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17222693</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Adv Virus Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">69</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>56669</offset><text>The baculoviruses occlusion-derived virus: virion structure and function</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1051</infon><infon key="lpage">1068</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:van Oers;given-names:MM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Vlak;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.2174/138945007782151333</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17979665</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Curr Drug Targets</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">8</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>56742</offset><text>Baculovirus genomics</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">6829</infon><infon key="lpage">6835</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Blissard;given-names:GW</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wenz;given-names:JR</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">1404622</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">66</infon><infon key="year">1992</infon><offset>56763</offset><text>Baculovirus gp64 envelope glycoprotein is sufficient to mediate pH-dependent membrane fusion</text></passage><passage><infon key="comment">Inc</infon><infon key="fpage">61</infon><infon key="lpage">107</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Williams;given-names:GFP</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Miller;given-names:LK</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">The baculoviruses</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>56856</offset><text>Cytological changes and viral morphogenesis during baculovirus infection</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">141</infon><infon key="lpage">153</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Young EAM;given-names:JC</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Faulkner;given-names:P</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1006/jsbi.1993.1015</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Struct Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">110</infon><infon key="year">1993</infon><offset>56929</offset><text>The architecture of the virogenic stroma in isolated nuclei of Spodoptera frugiperda cells in vitro infected by Autographa californica nuclear polyhedrosis virus</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">189</infon><infon key="lpage">195</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Fraser;given-names:MJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/0889-1605(86)90040-6</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Ultrastruct Mol Struct Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">95</infon><infon key="year">1986</infon><offset>57091</offset><text>Ultrastructural observations of virion maturation in Autographa californica nuclear polyhedrosis virus infected Spodoptera frugiperda cell cultures</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">103</infon><infon key="lpage">111</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Frost;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bourgaux;given-names:P</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1099/0022-1317-39-1-103</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">205626</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Gen Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">39</infon><infon key="year">1978</infon><offset>57239</offset><text>Structures of polyoma virus: on the histone component and virion core</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2805</infon><infon key="lpage">2809</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Tan;given-names:KB</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">197521</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">74</infon><infon key="year">1977</infon><offset>57309</offset><text>Histones: metabolism in simian virus 40-infected cells and incorporation into virions</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">13</infon><infon key="lpage">19</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pfister;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:zur Hausen;given-names:H</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/BF02121129</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">214677</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Med Microbiol Immunol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">166</infon><infon key="year">1978</infon><offset>57395</offset><text>Characterization of proteins of human papilloma viruses (HPV) and antibody response to HPV 1</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">552</infon><infon key="lpage">554</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lischwe;given-names:MA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Sung;given-names:MT</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/267552a0</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">876376</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nature</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">267</infon><infon key="year">1977</infon><offset>57488</offset><text>A histone-like protein from adenovirus chromatin</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1633</infon><infon key="lpage">1644</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chatterjee;given-names:PK</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Vayda;given-names:ME</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Flint;given-names:SJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">3743550</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">EMBO J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">5</infon><infon key="year">1986</infon><offset>57537</offset><text>Adenoviral protein VII packages intracellular viral DNA throughout the early phase of infection</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">197</infon><infon key="lpage">203</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Liu;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Wu;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chen;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hew;given-names:CL</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yan;given-names:J</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.virol.2010.09.008</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">20956009</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Virology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">408</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>57633</offset><text>DNA condensates organized by the capsid protein VP15 in white spot syndrome virus</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">866</infon><infon key="lpage">876</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Tweeten;given-names:KA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Bulla;given-names:LA</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Consigli;given-names:RA</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">16789190</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">33</infon><infon key="year">1980</infon><offset>57715</offset><text>Characterization of an extremely basic protein derived from granulosis virus nucleocapsids</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">353</infon><infon key="lpage">361</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lewis;given-names:JD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ausio;given-names:J</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1139/o02-083</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">12123288</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Biochem Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">80</infon><infon key="year">2002</infon><offset>57806</offset><text>Protamine-like proteins: evidence for a novel chromatin structure</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Brunner;given-names:AM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Nanni;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Mansuy;given-names:IM</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1186/1756-8935-7-2</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Epigenet Chromatin</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">7</infon><infon key="year">2014</infon><offset>57872</offset><text>Epigenetic marking of sperm by post-translational modification of histones and protamines</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1183</infon><infon key="lpage">1191</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Kelly;given-names:DC</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lescott;given-names:T</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1099/0022-1317-65-7-1183</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">6379101</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Gen Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">65</infon><infon key="year">1984</infon><offset>57962</offset><text>Baculovirus replication: phosphorylation of polypeptides synthesized in Trichoplusia ni nuclear polyhedrosis virus-infected cells</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">12217</infon><infon key="lpage">12227</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Liu;given-names:X</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zhao;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Fang;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Yuan;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yang;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Pang;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/JVI.00438-12</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22951830</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">86</infon><infon key="year">2012</infon><offset>58092</offset><text>Distribution and phosphorylation of the basic protein P6.9 of Autographa californica nucleopolyhedrovirus</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">7646</infon><infon key="lpage">7659</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Li;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zhao;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lai;given-names:Q</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Huang;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yuan;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Yang;given-names:K</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/JVI.00333-15</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25972542</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">89</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>58198</offset><text>Posttranslational modifications of baculovirus protamine-like protein P6.9 and the significance of its hyperphosphorylation for viral very late gene hyperexpression</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">396</infon><infon key="lpage">402</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Funk;given-names:CJ</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Consigli;given-names:RA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1006/viro.1993.1136</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8382403</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Virology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">193</infon><infon key="year">1993</infon><offset>58363</offset><text>Phosphate cycling on the basic protein of Plodia interpunctella granulosis virus</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1</infon><infon key="lpage">11</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Oppenheimer;given-names:DI</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Volkman;given-names:LE</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1006/viro.1995.1046</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">7871717</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Virology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">207</infon><infon key="year">1995</infon><offset>58444</offset><text>Proteolysis of p6.9 induced by cytochalasin D in Autographa californica M nuclear polyhedrosis virus-infected cells</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">211</infon><infon key="lpage">234</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Herniou;given-names:EA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Olszewski;given-names:JA</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Cory;given-names:JS</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:O'Reilly;given-names:DR</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1146/annurev.ento.48.091801.112756</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">12414741</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Annu Rev Entomol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">48</infon><infon key="year">2003</infon><offset>58560</offset><text>The genome sequence and evolution of baculoviruses</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">5395</infon><infon key="lpage">5406</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wang;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kleespies;given-names:RG</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Huger;given-names:AM</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Jehle;given-names:JA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/JVI.02781-06</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17360757</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">81</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>58611</offset><text>The genome of Gryllus bimaculatus nudivirus indicates an ancient diversification of baculovirus-related nonoccluded nudiviruses of insects</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">187</infon><infon key="lpage">193</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wang;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Jehle;given-names:JA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jip.2009.03.013</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">19460388</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Invertebr Pathol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">101</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>58750</offset><text>Nudiviruses and other large, double-stranded circular DNA viruses of invertebrates: new insights on an old topic</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">926</infon><infon key="lpage">930</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Bezier;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Annaheim;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_10">surname:Pfister-Wilhem;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_11">surname:Periquet;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_12">surname:Dupuy;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_13">surname:Huguet;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_14">surname:Volkoff;given-names:AN</infon><infon key="name_15">surname:Lanzrein;given-names:B</infon><infon key="name_16">surname:Drezen;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Herbiniere;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wetterwald;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Gyapay;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Bernard-Samain;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Wincker;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Roditi;given-names:I</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Heller;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Belghazi;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1126/science.1166788</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">19213916</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Science</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">323</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>58863</offset><text>Polydnaviruses of braconid wasps derive from an ancestral nudivirus</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1003</infon><infon key="lpage">1034</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Burroughs;given-names:AM</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Allen;given-names:KN</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Dunaway-Mariano;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Aravind;given-names:L</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/j.jmb.2006.06.049</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">16889794</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Mol Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">361</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>58931</offset><text>Evolutionary genomics of the HAD superfamily: understanding the structural adaptations and catalytic diversity in a superfamily of phosphoesterases and allied enzymes</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">11475</infon><infon key="lpage">11485</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wu;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lin;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Pan;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Yu;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Li;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Pang;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Yang;given-names:K</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/JVI.01155-06</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">16987976</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">80</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>59098</offset><text>Autographa californica multiple nucleopolyhedrovirus nucleocapsid assembly is interrupted upon deletion of the 38K gene</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">127</infon><infon key="lpage">129</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Aravind;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Galperin;given-names:MY</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Koonin;given-names:EV</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/S0968-0004(98)01189-X</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">9584613</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Trends Biochem Sci</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">23</infon><infon key="year">1998</infon><offset>59218</offset><text>The catalytic domain of the P-type ATPase has the haloacid dehalogenase fold</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">D222</infon><infon key="lpage">D226</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Marchler-Bauer;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Derbyshire;given-names:MK</infon><infon key="name_10">surname:Lanczycki;given-names:CJ</infon><infon key="name_11">surname:Lu;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_12">surname:Marchler;given-names:GH</infon><infon key="name_13">surname:Song;given-names:JS</infon><infon key="name_14">surname:Thanki;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_15">surname:Wang;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="name_16">surname:Yamashita;given-names:RA</infon><infon key="name_17">surname:Zhang;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_18">surname:Zheng;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_19">surname:Bryant;given-names:SH</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gonzales;given-names:NR</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Lu;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Chitsaz;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Geer;given-names:LY</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Geer;given-names:RC</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:He;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Gwadz;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Hurwitz;given-names:DI</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/nar/gku1221</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">25414356</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nucleic Acids Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">43</infon><infon key="year">2015</infon><offset>59295</offset><text>CDD: NCBI's conserved domain database</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">12704</infon><infon key="lpage">12711</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Selengut;given-names:JD</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1021/bi011405e</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">11601995</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Biochemistry</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">40</infon><infon key="year">2001</infon><offset>59333</offset><text>MDP-1 is a new and distinct member of the haloacid dehalogenase family of aspartate-dependent phosphohydrolases</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">125</infon><infon key="lpage">132</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Koonin;given-names:EV</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tatusov;given-names:RL</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">7966317</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Mol Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">244</infon><infon key="year">1994</infon><offset>59445</offset><text>Computer analysis of bacterial haloacid dehalogenases defines a large superfamily of hydrolases with diverse specificity. Application of an iterative approach to database search</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1724</infon><infon key="lpage">1733</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Vanarsdall;given-names:AL</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Okano;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Rohrmann;given-names:GF</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/JVI.80.4.1724-1733.2006</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">16439529</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">80</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>59623</offset><text>Characterization of the role of very late expression factor 1 in baculovirus capsid structure and DNA processing</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">4607</infon><infon key="lpage">4616</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Monsma;given-names:SA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Oomens;given-names:AG</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Blissard;given-names:GW</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8676487</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">70</infon><infon key="year">1996</infon><offset>59736</offset><text>The GP64 envelope fusion protein is an essential baculovirus protein required for cell-to-cell transmission of infection</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">315</infon><infon key="lpage">328</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wilson;given-names:ME</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Miller;given-names:LK</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/0042-6822(86)90052-8</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">3518228</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Virology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">151</infon><infon key="year">1986</infon><offset>59857</offset><text>Changes in the nucleoprotein complexes of a baculovirus DNA during infection</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2861</infon><infon key="lpage">2869</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Locker;given-names:CR</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Fuller;given-names:SD</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Harvey;given-names:SC</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1529/biophysj.106.094771</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17573426</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Biophys J</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">93</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>59934</offset><text>DNA organization and thermodynamics during viral packing</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1484</infon><infon key="lpage">1497</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Roos;given-names:WH</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Ivanovska;given-names:IL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Evilevitch;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wuite;given-names:GJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s00018-007-6451-1</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17440680</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Cell Mol Life Sci</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">64</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>59991</offset><text>Viral capsids: mechanical characteristics, genome packaging and delivery mechanisms</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">886</infon><infon key="lpage">903</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Guo;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Lee;given-names:TJ</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1111/j.1365-2958.2007.05706.x</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17501915</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Mol Microbiol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">64</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>60075</offset><text>Viral nanomotors for packaging of dsDNA and dsRNA</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">11245</infon><infon key="lpage">11250</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Fuller;given-names:DN</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Rickgauer;given-names:JP</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Jardine;given-names:PJ</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Grimes;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Anderson;given-names:DL</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Smith;given-names:DE</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1073/pnas.0701323104</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17556543</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">104</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>60125</offset><text>Ionic effects on viral DNA packaging and portal motor function in bacteriophage phi 29</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">120</infon><infon key="lpage">123</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Brewer;given-names:LR</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Corzett;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Balhorn;given-names:R</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1126/science.286.5437.120</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">10506559</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Science</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">286</infon><infon key="year">1999</infon><offset>60212</offset><text>Protamine-induced condensation and decondensation of the same DNA molecule</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">661</infon><infon key="lpage">666</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wilson;given-names:ME</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Mainprize;given-names:TH</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Friesen;given-names:PD</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Miller;given-names:LK</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">3543402</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">61</infon><infon key="year">1987</infon><offset>60287</offset><text>Location, transcription, and sequence of a baculovirus gene encoding a small arginine-rich polypeptide</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">526</infon><infon key="lpage">535</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wilson;given-names:ME</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Consigli;given-names:RA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/0042-6822(85)90391-5</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">18639856</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Virology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">143</infon><infon key="year">1985</infon><offset>60390</offset><text>Functions of a protein kinase activity associated with purified capsids of the granulosis virus infecting Plodia interpunctella</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">516</infon><infon key="lpage">525</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wilson;given-names:ME</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Consigli;given-names:RA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/0042-6822(85)90390-3</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">18639855</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Virology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">143</infon><infon key="year">1985</infon><offset>60518</offset><text>Characterization of a protein kinase activity associated with purified capsids of the granulosis virus infecting Plodia interpunctella</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">807</infon><infon key="lpage">810</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Maeda;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kamita;given-names:SG</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kataoka;given-names:H</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/0042-6822(91)90096-T</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">1703373</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Virology</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">180</infon><infon key="year">1991</infon><offset>60653</offset><text>The basic DNA-binding protein of Bombyx mori nuclear polyhedrosis virus: the existence of an additional arginine repeat</text></passage><passage><infon key="elocation-id">e02115-</infon><infon key="lpage">16</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Javed;given-names:MA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Biswas;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Willis;given-names:LG</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Harris;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Pritchard;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:van Oers;given-names:MM</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Donly;given-names:BC</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Erlandson;given-names:MA</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Hegedus;given-names:DD</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Theilmann;given-names:DA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/JVI.02115-16</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">28031365</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">91</infon><infon key="year">2017</infon><offset>60773</offset><text>Autographa californica multiple nucleopolyhedrovirus AC83 is a per os infectivity factor (PIF) protein required for occlusion-derived virus (ODV) and budded virus nucleocapsid assembly as well as assembly of the PIF complex in ODV envelopes</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">12356</infon><infon key="lpage">12364</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wu;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Liang;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kan;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Liu;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yuan;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Liang;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Yang;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Pang;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/JVI.00948-08</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">18922869</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">82</infon><infon key="year">2008</infon><offset>61014</offset><text>Autographa californica multiple nucleopolyhedrovirus 38K is a novel nucleocapsid protein that interacts with VP1054, VP39, VP80, and itself</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">33985</infon><infon key="lpage">33990</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Collet;given-names:JF</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Stroobant;given-names:V</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Van Schaftingen;given-names:E</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1074/jbc.274.48.33985</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">10567362</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Biol Chem</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">274</infon><infon key="year">1999</infon><offset>61154</offset><text>Mechanistic studies of phosphoserine phosphatase, an enzyme related to P-type ATPases</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">8315</infon><infon key="lpage">8324</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Selengut;given-names:JD</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Levine;given-names:RL</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1021/bi0005052</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">10889041</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Biochemistry</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">39</infon><infon key="year">2000</infon><offset>61240</offset><text>MDP-1: a novel eukaryotic magnesium-dependent phosphatase</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">157</infon><infon key="lpage">163</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Hefferon;given-names:KL</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1139/w03-022</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">12795401</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Can J Microbiol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">49</infon><infon key="year">2003</infon><offset>61298</offset><text>ORF98 of Autographa californica nucleopolyhedrosisvirus is an auxiliary factor in late gene expression</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">725</infon><infon key="lpage">738</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Roy;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kucukural;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Zhang;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/nprot.2010.5</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">20360767</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat Protoc</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">5</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>61401</offset><text>I-TASSER: a unified platform for automated protein structure and function prediction</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">8821</infon><infon key="lpage">8828</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Wang;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tuladhar;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Shen;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wang;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:van Oers;given-names:MM</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Vlak;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Westenberg;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/JVI.00072-10</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">20519380</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">84</infon><infon key="year">2010</infon><offset>61486</offset><text>Specificity of baculovirus P6.9 basic DNA-binding proteins and critical role of the C terminus in virion formation</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">655</infon><infon key="lpage">663</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Lu;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Carstens;given-names:EB</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">1731106</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">66</infon><infon key="year">1992</infon><offset>61601</offset><text>Transcription analysis of the EcoRI D region of the baculovirus Autographa californica nuclear polyhedrosis virus identifies an early 4-kilobase RNA encoding the essential p143 gene</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2972</infon><infon key="lpage">2980</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Papoutsopoulou;given-names:S</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Nikolakaki;given-names:E</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Chalepakis;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Kruft;given-names:V</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Chevaillier;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Giannakouros;given-names:T</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/nar/27.14.2972</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">10390541</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nucleic Acids Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">27</infon><infon key="year">1999</infon><offset>61783</offset><text>SR protein-specific kinase 1 is highly expressed in testis and phosphorylates protamine 1</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">298</infon><infon key="lpage">305</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Balhorn;given-names:R</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1083/jcb.93.2.298</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">7096440</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Cell Biol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">93</infon><infon key="year">1982</infon><offset>61873</offset><text>A model for the structure of chromatin in mammalian sperm</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">981</infon><infon key="lpage">986</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Pirhonen;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Linnala-Kankkunen;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Maenpaa;given-names:PH</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1095/biolreprod50.5.981</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">8025177</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Biol Reprod</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">50</infon><infon key="year">1994</infon><offset>61931</offset><text>Identification of phosphoseryl residues in protamines from mature mammalian spermatozoa</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1121</infon><infon key="lpage">1133</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Witteveldt;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Vermeesch;given-names:AM</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Langenhof;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:de Lang;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Vlak;given-names:JM</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:van Hulten;given-names:MC</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1007/s00705-004-0483-8</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">15703849</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Arch Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">150</infon><infon key="year">2005</infon><offset>62019</offset><text>Nucleocapsid protein VP15 is the basic DNA binding protein of white spot syndrome virus of shrimp</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2708</infon><infon key="lpage">2714</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Tan;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Spears;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Bideshi;given-names:DK</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Johnson;given-names:JJ</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Hice;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Bigot;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Federici;given-names:BA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/JVI.01610-08</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">19129454</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">83</infon><infon key="year">2009</infon><offset>62117</offset><text>P64, a novel major virion DNA-binding protein potentially involved in condensing the Spodoptera frugiperda ascovirus 1a genome</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">6459</infon><infon key="lpage">6468</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Johnson;given-names:JS</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Osheim;given-names:YN</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Xue;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Emanuel;given-names:MR</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Lewis;given-names:PW</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Bankovich;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Beyer;given-names:AL</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Engel;given-names:DA</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/JVI.78.12.6459-6468.2004</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">15163739</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">78</infon><infon key="year">2004</infon><offset>62244</offset><text>Adenovirus protein VII condenses DNA, represses transcription, and associates with transcriptional activator E1A</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">173</infon><infon key="lpage">177</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Avgousti;given-names:DC</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Herrmann;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_10">surname:Ostapchuk;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_11">surname:Hearing;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_12">surname:Seeholzer;given-names:SH</infon><infon key="name_13">surname:Worthen;given-names:GS</infon><infon key="name_14">surname:Black;given-names:BE</infon><infon key="name_15">surname:Garcia;given-names:BA</infon><infon key="name_16">surname:Weitzman;given-names:MD</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Kulej;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Pancholi;given-names:NJ</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Sekulic;given-names:N</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Petrescu;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Molden;given-names:RC</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Blumenthal;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Paris;given-names:AJ</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Reyes;given-names:ED</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/nature18317</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">27362237</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nature</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">535</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>62357</offset><text>A core viral protein binds host nucleosomes to sequester immune danger signals</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">4115</infon><infon key="lpage">4126</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Guan;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Zhong;given-names:L</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Li;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Wu;given-names:W</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yuan;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Yang;given-names:K</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/JVI.02885-15</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">26865720</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">90</infon><infon key="year">2016</infon><offset>62436</offset><text>The Autographa californica multiple nucleopolyhedrovirus ac54 gene is crucial for localization of the major capsid protein VP39 at the site of nucleocapsid assembly</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2947</infon><infon key="lpage">2948</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Larkin;given-names:MA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Blackshields;given-names:G</infon><infon key="name_10">surname:Thompson;given-names:JD</infon><infon key="name_11">surname:Gibson;given-names:TJ</infon><infon key="name_12">surname:Higgins;given-names:DG</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Brown;given-names:NP</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Chenna;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:McGettigan;given-names:PA</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:McWilliam;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Valentin;given-names:F</infon><infon key="name_7">surname:Wallace;given-names:IM</infon><infon key="name_8">surname:Wilm;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_9">surname:Lopez;given-names:R</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/bioinformatics/btm404</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17846036</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Bioinformatics</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">23</infon><infon key="year">2007</infon><offset>62601</offset><text>Clustal W and Clustal X version 2.0</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">14</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Nicholas KB;given-names:NH</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Deerfield;given-names:DW</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">EMBNEW News</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">4</infon><infon key="year">1997</infon><offset>62637</offset><text>GeneDoc: analysis and visualization of genetic variation</text></passage><passage><infon key="elocation-id">e174</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Chiu;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:March;given-names:PE</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Lee;given-names:R</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Tillett;given-names:D</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1093/nar/gnh172</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">15585660</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nucleic Acids Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">32</infon><infon key="year">2004</infon><offset>62694</offset><text>Site-directed, ligase-independent mutagenesis (SLIM): a single-tube methodology approaching 100% efficiency in 4 h</text></passage><passage><infon key="name_0">surname:O'Reilly DR;given-names:ML</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Luckow;given-names:VA</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Baculovirus expression vetors: a laboratory manual</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="year">1992</infon><offset>62809</offset></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">11664</infon><infon key="lpage">11674</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Yuan;given-names:M</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Huang;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Wei;given-names:D</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Hu;given-names:Z</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Yang;given-names:K</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Pang;given-names:Y</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1128/JVI.05275-11</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">21880748</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Virol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">85</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>62810</offset><text>Identification of Autographa californica nucleopolyhedrovirus ac93 as a core gene and its requirement for intranuclear microvesicle formation and nuclear egress of nucleocapsids</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">2856</infon><infon key="lpage">2860</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Shevchenko;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Tomas;given-names:H</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Havlis;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Olsen;given-names:JV</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Mann;given-names:M</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/nprot.2006.468</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">17406544</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat Protoc</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">1</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>62988</offset><text>In-gel digestion for mass spectrometric characterization of proteins and proteomes</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">976</infon><infon key="lpage">989</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Eng;given-names:JK</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:McCormack;given-names:AL</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Yates;given-names:JR</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1016/1044-0305(94)80016-2</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">24226387</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Am Soc Mass Spectrom</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">5</infon><infon key="year">1994</infon><offset>63071</offset><text>An approach to correlate tandem mass spectral data of peptides with amino acid sequences in a protein database</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">5354</infon><infon key="lpage">5362</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Taus;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Kocher;given-names:T</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Pichler;given-names:P</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Paschke;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Schmidt;given-names:A</infon><infon key="name_5">surname:Henrich;given-names:C</infon><infon key="name_6">surname:Mechtler;given-names:K</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1021/pr200611n</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">22073976</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">J Proteome Res</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">10</infon><infon key="year">2011</infon><offset>63182</offset><text>Universal and confident phosphorylation site localization using phosphoRS</text></passage><passage><infon key="fpage">1285</infon><infon key="lpage">1292</infon><infon key="name_0">surname:Beausoleil;given-names:SA</infon><infon key="name_1">surname:Villen;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_2">surname:Gerber;given-names:SA</infon><infon key="name_3">surname:Rush;given-names:J</infon><infon key="name_4">surname:Gygi;given-names:SP</infon><infon key="pub-id_doi">10.1038/nbt1240</infon><infon key="pub-id_pmid">16964243</infon><infon key="section_type">REF</infon><infon key="source">Nat Biotechnol</infon><infon key="type">ref</infon><infon key="volume">24</infon><infon key="year">2006</infon><offset>63256</offset><text>A probability-based approach for high-throughput protein phosphorylation analysis and site localization</text></passage></document>
</collection>